ALEXANDRE BERNHARDT

 $\underline{al.bernhardt@gmail.com}$

+33 (0)6 77 79 05 22

JAVA - PHP DEVELOPER

Profile

Engineering software developer in the field of web and embedded applications. Specialised in development methodologies necessary to perpetuate the information systems in business.

Skills

Analysis

Analyze the business requirements to build precise technical specifications. Modelize these needs and select appropriate technologies.

IT Development

Develop applications leverage existing functionality to meet business requirements.

Support

Help users to have the best experience with applications, maintain the IT solutions.

Technical

Java / J2EE	PHP	MERISE
C#	XHTML (HTML 5)	UML
C / C++	CSS	Java Design Pattern
Visual Basic	JavaScript	OS X
SDK Android	Wordpress, Joomla	Windows XP/Vista/7
Spring MVC	Y ii framework	Windows Server 2003/2008
Grails	CVS / SVN	Linux

Experience

Neurones Technologie S.A., Geneva, Switzerland Developer / Consultant

April 2009 - June 2012

IT Services company specializing in development and integration of information systems, business management. Development of web-based business applications such as Secured Intranet, Information Reporting, HR Quiz, ... (PHP, My/MsSQL, Yii framwork, Wordpress, Joomla, Netbeans)

Development of multiple intranet and extranet portals using Liferay. Development of extensions, hooks, themes and portlets. (Java/J2EE, Eclipse, Hibernate, Velocity, JSP, My/MsSQL)

Scheuchzer S.A., Lausanne, Switzerland Java Developer

January 2010 - November 2011

Customer based mandate for Neurones Technologies SA, to develop various projects. Designing a GUI SWT / Eclipse content management application, data entry and reporting, databases connectors and deployment of the applications. (Java, SWT, JDBC, SQL Server)

CSPQ - Directorate General of Telecommunication April 2008 - June 2008 Networks, Quebec, Canada

Trainee Developer

3-month internship for the Government of Quebec; improvement of existing applications and development of a LAN management application in C #. Management applications of microwave network in the province of Quebec (Wireless network to scale the country). (C#, VB, Microsoft Visual Studio)

Education

Franche Comté University - Belfort, France

2008 — University Diploma in Technology (DUT), Computer Engineering

2006 — First year of University Diploma in Technology (DUT), Industrial Electrical and Computer Engineering (GEII)

Scheurer-Kestner High School - Thann, France

2005 — Bachelor of Science, option Physics - Chemistry

Hobbies

Scuba diving — CMAS Diver N1 degree (PE2)

Fencing — Blue shield (3rd level) Musique — Piano and guitar player

Alexandre Bernhardt — al.bernhardt@gmail.com — +33 (0)6 77 79 05 22